There is a day.
About ten years ago when I asked a
friend to hold a baby dinosaur
robot upside down.
It was a toy called plea.
All that he'd ordered and I was
really excited about it because
I've always loved about this one
has really caught technical
features.
It had more orders and touch
sensors.
It had an infra red camera and one
of the things that had was a tilt
sensor so it.
Knew what direction.
It was facing.
If and when you held it upside
down.
I thought.
It's a super courts are showing
off to my friend and I said to
hold it, but he'll see what debts.
We were watching the theatrics of
this robe that struggle and cry
out and and after a few seconds.
The first.
After my little and I said o.k.
That's enough.
Now, let's put him back down and
pepper, about to make it.
Stop crying and I was kind of a
weird experience for me one thing,
wasn't the most maternal person at
the time.
Although, since then I've become a
mother and nine months ago.
And that is a score when hold them
up to now, but my response to this
robot was also interesting because
I knew exactly how this machine
work it.
And yet.
I still felt compelled to be kind
to it.
And that observation sparked that
curiosity that I spent the fat,
the past decade pursuing it.
Why did they comfort this robe.
One of the things I discovered was
that my treatment of this machine
was more than just an awkward
moment in my living room that in a
world were increasingly
integrating robots into our lives
and things like that might
actually have consequences because
the first thing that I discovered
is that.
It's not just me in two thousand
seven.
The Washington Post reported that
the United States military was
testing this robot diffused
landmines.
We workers were shaped like a
stick insect would walk around a
minefield on its legs and every
time he stepped on a mine.
One of the legs would blow up
would continue on the other legs
to block your minds in the colonel
was in charge of this testing
exercise for calling it off
because he says it's too inhumane
to watch this damage robot drag
itself along the minefield.
What would cause a hardened
military officer and someone like
myself to have this response to
row.
But what.
Of course for prime for science
fiction, pop culture really want
to personify these things, but it
goes a little bit deeper than that
it turns out that we are
biologically hard wired to project
intent and life onto any movement
in a physical space.
It seems I promised us some people
treat all sort of robots like
their life.
These bomb disposal units get
names.
They get medals of honour had
funeral for them with gun salutes.
Research shows that we do this.
Even with very simple household
robots like the room.
A vacuum cleaner.
Just a desk that runs around the
floor and clean it just the fact
that it's moving around on his own
will cause people to name the
marimba and feel bad for the room.
But when he gets stuck under the
couch.
We can design about specifically
to invoke this response using eyes
and faces were movement.
People are magically
subconsciously associate with
state of mind.
There's an entire body of research
called Human robot interaction
that really shows how all this
works so.
For example.
Researchers at Stamford University
found out that makes people really
uncomfortable and asked them to
touch her about his private parts
from this from any other studies.
We know.
We know that people respond to the
cues given to them by the lifelike
machines.
Even if they know that they're not
real.
We're heading towards a world
where robots are everywhere about
the technology is moving out from
behind factory was entering
workplaces households and as these
machines.
They can sense and make a ton of
my decisions and learn enter into
the shared spaces.
I think that maybe the best
analogy.
We have for this is our
relationship with animals.
Thousands of years ago, we started
to domesticate animals and we
train them for work and weaponry
and companionship.
Throughout history.
We've treated.
Some animals like tools are the
products and other animals.
We treated with kindness and given
a place in society as our
companions.
I think it's possible.
We might start to integrate
Robartes, but similar weights
animals are alive.
Robert and that.
And I can tell you from working.
What about the sister were pretty
far away from developing robots.
They can feel anything there, but
we feel for that.
And that matters because if we're
trying to integrate robots into
the shared spaces need to
understand that people treat them
differently than other devices
that in some cases.
For example, the case of a soldier
who becomes emotionally attached
to the robot.
They work.
Well, if that can be anything from
inefficient to dangerous.
But in other cases.
It can actually be used for the
faster this emotional connection
to, but we're really seeing some
great use cases.
For example, robots working with
autistic children to engage them
in ways that we haven't seen
previously robot's working with
teachers to engage kids and learn
with new results and it's not just
for kids early studies show that
we can help doctors and patients
and health care settings and this
is the pirate b. b. c. But it's
used in nursing homes with
dementia patients has been around
for a while I remember years ago.
Being a party and telling someone
about this throwback and her
response was on my cart.
I can't believe we're giving
people robots instead of human
care.
And this is a really common
response and I think it's
absolutely correct because that
would be terrible.
And in this case.
It's not with this robot replace
it with this robot replaces his
animal therapy in context which he
was real animals.
We can use robots because people
consistently treat them like more.
More like an animal and have it
acknowledging this emotional
connection.
Robert, can also help us
anticipate challenges as these
devices.
Move into more intimate areas of
people's lives and for example is
it.
o.k.
If your child's teddy bear robot
records private conversations.
Is it.
o.k.
If your sex robot has compelling
in our purchasers because rope.
That's plus capitalism equals
questions around consumer
protection and privacy and those
aren't the only reason, said her
behaviour around these machines
could, madam.
A few years after that first
initial experience.
I had with this baby dinosaur
robot do workshop with her friend
Hannah Scott.
Scott, then we took five of these
baby dinosaur about we give them.
The five teams of people.
We had the name them and play with
them and interact with them for
about an hour.
Then we unveiled a him or a
hatchet and we told them to
torture and kill the row and then
this turned out to be a little
more dramatic than we expected it
to be because none of the
participants wouldn't even so much
as straight.
A robot.
So we had to improvise.
End at some point.
He said o.k.
You can save your team's robot.
If you destroy another team throw.
I I. And anyone that didn't work.
They couldn't do it.
So finally said, We're gonna
destroy all the robots are someone
takes a hatchet to one of them.
This guy stood up and he took the
hatchet and the whole room,
Winston.
See brother had to down on the
robot's neck and there was this
half joking.
Half serious moment of silence in
the room from this farm and but so
that was a really interesting
experience.
It wasn't a controlled study up
your sleeve, but it did lead to
some leader research that I did.
i. t. With plush, London.
Cynthia busy.
Or we had people come into the lab
and smash these Hex bugs that move
around in a really lifelike way,
like insects.
So instead of choosing something
huge.
People are trying to reach for
something more basic.
And what we found was that high
embassy people would hesitate,
more hit the heck's bucks.
This is just a little study, but
it's part of a large body of
research that is starting to
indicate that there may be a
connection between people's
tendencies for empathy and their
behaviour around, Rover.
But my question for the coming era
of human robot interaction is not
to.
We empathise with throw, but it.
Can robots change people's
thinking, Is there reason to.
For example, prevent the child
from kicking about Doc That just
out of respect for property
because the child may be more
likely to take a real dark and
again.
It's not just kids and this is the
violent video games question, but
it's a completely new level
because of this visceral
physicality that we respond more
intensely.
Two images on a screen, we behave
violently towards Robarts
specifically robots that are
designed to mimic life is that a
healthy outlook from the behaviour
or is that training cruelty
muscles.
The answer to this question has
the potential impact human
behaviour has the potential impact
social norms.
It has the potential to inspire
rules around.
What we can and can't do certain
Robarts animal cruelty, but
because even if robots can't fuel
our behaviour towards a matter for
us and regardless of whether we
end up changing ovals robots might
be able to help us come to a new
understanding of ourselves.
Most of what learned over the past
ten years have not been about
technology.
A It's been about human psychology
and empathy and how we relate to
others.
And because when a child is kind
to her room.
But when a soldier tries to save a
robot on the battlefield.
When a group of people refuses to
harm her about a baby dinosaur.
Those robots aren't just motors in
years and a groom's.
Their reflections of our own
humanity.